<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<learningOutcomes xmlns="http://canvas.instructure.com/xsd/cccv1p0"
                  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                  xsi:schemaLocation="http://canvas.instructure.com/xsd/cccv1p0 http://canvas.instructure.com/xsd/cccv1p0.xsd">

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       TOOL TIME UNIVERSITY - LEARNING OUTCOMES

       Course Learning Outcomes aligned with:
       - Television Studies competencies
       - Cultural Analysis skills
       - Critical Thinking development
       - Creative Writing proficiency

       Mastery Scale: Home Equity Performance Levels
       - Master Craftsman (4): Exceeds expectations - expert level
       - Journeyman Builder (3): Meets expectations - proficient
       - Apprentice (2): Approaching expectations - developing
       - Weekend Warrior (1): Below expectations - beginning
       - Tim After a Disaster (0): Not demonstrated
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       OUTCOME GROUP: MEDIA ANALYSIS
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <learningOutcomeGroup identifier="og_media_analysis">
    <title>Media Analysis: The Tool Time Method</title>
    <description>Competencies in analyzing television as a cultural medium, including narrative structure, character development, and production elements.</description>

    <!-- Outcome 1: Narrative Structure Analysis -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_narrative_structure">
      <title>Analyze Narrative Structure in Sitcom Format</title>
      <description>Students will identify and analyze the three-act structure, A/B storylines, and comedic timing in sitcom episodes, using Home Improvement as the primary text.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Demonstrates expert understanding of sitcom structure. Identifies subtle narrative techniques, explains how structure serves thematic goals, and draws connections across multiple episodes and seasons.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficiently analyzes episode structure. Identifies main and sub-plots, recognizes standard comedic beats, and explains how structure contributes to humor and character development.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing understanding of episode structure. Can identify basic story elements but may miss nuance in how plots interweave or how structure supports theme.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning to recognize narrative elements. Identifies obvious plot points but struggles to analyze how they function within the episode's overall design.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating understanding of narrative structure.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>ttc_mod01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>ttc_mod08</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>final_episode</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- Outcome 2: Character Development Analysis -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_character_development">
      <title>Evaluate Character Development Across Series</title>
      <description>Students will trace character arcs across 8 seasons, analyzing how characters grow, change, and maintain consistency within the sitcom format.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Expert analysis of character trajectories. Identifies subtle character moments, explains how actors' performances shape characterization, and articulates how character growth reflects broader series themes.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficiently tracks character development. Identifies key growth moments, explains character motivations, and connects character arcs to series-long themes.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing ability to analyze characters. Recognizes obvious character traits and major changes but may miss subtlety in how characters evolve.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning character analysis. Can describe characters but struggles to explain their development or connect their growth to larger patterns.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating character analysis skills.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>ttc_mod03</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>bpc_mod07</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>final_episode</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- Outcome 3: Production Elements -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_production_elements">
      <title>Identify Television Production Elements</title>
      <description>Students will recognize and explain how production elements (set design, lighting, sound, editing) contribute to the sitcom's comedic and emotional effects.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Expert understanding of production craft. Identifies how Tool Time's show-within-a-show format serves narrative purposes, analyzes how production choices evolved across seasons, and explains technical comedy.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficient recognition of production elements. Understands how sets, costumes, and staging contribute to humor and character definition.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing awareness of production. Notices obvious elements like the Tool Time set but may not fully explain their significance.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning to notice production. Recognizes that choices were made but struggles to analyze their purpose.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating production awareness.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>bpc_mod01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>bpc_mod03</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>
  </learningOutcomeGroup>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       OUTCOME GROUP: CULTURAL ANALYSIS
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <learningOutcomeGroup identifier="og_cultural_analysis">
    <title>Cultural Analysis: Wilson's Way</title>
    <description>Competencies in analyzing television's relationship to broader cultural contexts, including historical period, social values, and audience reception.</description>

    <!-- Outcome 4: Historical Context -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_historical_context">
      <title>Contextualize Television Within Historical Period</title>
      <description>Students will analyze how Home Improvement reflects and responds to 1990s American culture, including family values, gender roles, and technological change.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Expert historical contextualization. Draws sophisticated connections between the show and its era, explains how the series both reflected and shaped cultural attitudes, and identifies how the show's perspective has aged.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficiently places the show in historical context. Identifies key cultural touchstones, explains how the show addressed contemporary issues, and recognizes period-specific elements.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing historical awareness. Recognizes that the show is a product of its time but may struggle to articulate specific connections to 90s culture.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning historical thinking. Notices the show is "dated" but can't fully explain what that means culturally.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating historical contextualization.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>ttc_mod06</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>ttc_mod02</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- Outcome 5: Gender Analysis -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_gender_analysis">
      <title>Analyze Representations of Gender and Family</title>
      <description>Students will critically examine how Home Improvement portrays masculinity, femininity, marriage, and family dynamics, identifying both progressive and problematic elements.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Nuanced gender analysis. Identifies complex portrayals of masculinity and femininity, explains how Tim and Jill's relationship subverts and reinforces stereotypes, and articulates how the show's gender politics evolved.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficient gender awareness. Recognizes gendered patterns in character behavior, explains the "Men Are Pigs" thesis, and identifies how parenting roles are distributed.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing gender lens. Notices obvious gender dynamics but may not fully analyze their implications or evolution.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning gender awareness. Recognizes that gender is relevant but struggles to apply analytical frameworks.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating gender analysis.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>ttc_mod04</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>wr_01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- Outcome 6: Philosophy Integration -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_philosophy_integration">
      <title>Connect Popular Culture to Philosophical Concepts</title>
      <description>Students will identify and explain how Wilson's philosophical references illuminate the show's themes, demonstrating ability to connect entertainment media to intellectual traditions.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Expert philosophical integration. Traces Wilson's references to their sources, explains how philosophy functions within the show's moral framework, and applies philosophical concepts to analyze episodes independently.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficient philosophical awareness. Recognizes major philosophical traditions Wilson draws from, explains how his advice connects to episode themes, and identifies the show's implicit values.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing philosophical connection. Notices that Wilson quotes philosophers but may not fully understand or apply the referenced ideas.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning philosophical awareness. Recognizes Wilson is "wise" but can't explain the intellectual sources of his wisdom.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating philosophical integration.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>wr_01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>wr_02</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>disc_mod01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>
  </learningOutcomeGroup>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       OUTCOME GROUP: CRITICAL THINKING
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <learningOutcomeGroup identifier="og_critical_thinking">
    <title>Critical Thinking: Al's Approach</title>
    <description>Core analytical competencies applied to media study, including evidence-based argumentation, synthesis, and evaluation.</description>

    <!-- Outcome 7: Evidence-Based Analysis -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_evidence_analysis">
      <title>Support Arguments with Textual Evidence</title>
      <description>Students will construct arguments about Home Improvement using specific evidence from episodes, demonstrating ability to move from observation to interpretation.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Exemplary evidence use. Selects the most relevant moments to support claims, integrates evidence smoothly into argument, and acknowledges counter-evidence where appropriate.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficient evidence integration. Uses specific examples from episodes to support claims, explains how evidence connects to argument, and provides sufficient support for conclusions.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing evidence skills. Includes examples but may not fully explain their relevance or may rely on summary rather than analysis.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning evidence use. Makes claims but provides limited or tangential support from the show itself.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating evidence-based analysis.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>ttc_mod01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>bpc_mod01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>final_episode</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- Outcome 8: Synthesis -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_synthesis">
      <title>Synthesize Information Across Multiple Sources</title>
      <description>Students will integrate observations across multiple episodes, seasons, and external sources to build comprehensive understanding of series themes and patterns.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Exceptional synthesis. Draws connections across the full series, integrates external research seamlessly, and produces insights that demonstrate comprehensive understanding.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficient synthesis. Connects observations across multiple episodes, incorporates relevant external information, and identifies patterns that span seasons.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing synthesis. Makes some connections between sources but may treat episodes or information in isolation rather than as part of larger patterns.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning synthesis. Focuses on individual episodes without connecting to broader series context.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating synthesis.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>bpc_mod05</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>ttc_mod06</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>final_episode</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>
  </learningOutcomeGroup>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       OUTCOME GROUP: CREATIVE WRITING
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <learningOutcomeGroup identifier="og_creative_writing">
    <title>Creative Writing: More Power to Your Prose</title>
    <description>Competencies in creative and analytical writing, including voice capture, format mastery, and effective communication.</description>

    <!-- Outcome 9: Voice Capture -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_voice_capture">
      <title>Capture Character Voice in Creative Writing</title>
      <description>Students will demonstrate ability to write in established characters' voices, maintaining consistency with established personalities while creating original content.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Exemplary voice capture. Characters sound authentic, distinct from each other, and consistent with their established personalities. Original dialogue feels like it could appear in the actual series.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficient voice work. Characters are recognizable and dialogue captures key verbal patterns (Tim's grunts, Al's "I don't think so, Tim," Wilson's philosophical framing).</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing voice awareness. Attempts character voice but may be inconsistent or rely too heavily on catchphrases without capturing underlying personality.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning voice work. Characters are somewhat generic or don't clearly differentiate from each other in dialogue.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating voice capture.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>final_episode</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>bpc_mod01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- Outcome 10: Clear Communication -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_clear_communication">
      <title>Communicate Ideas Clearly and Effectively</title>
      <description>Students will express analytical ideas in clear, organized prose with appropriate academic tone and mechanical correctness.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>4</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Master Craftsman: Exemplary communication. Writing is clear, engaging, and well-organized. Arguments flow logically, transitions are smooth, and mechanical errors are rare.</description>
          <points>4</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Journeyman Builder: Proficient communication. Writing is clear and organized with appropriate academic tone. Minor errors don't impede understanding.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Apprentice: Developing communication. Ideas are present but organization or clarity may be inconsistent. Some errors affect readability.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Weekend Warrior: Beginning communication. Writing may be unclear, disorganized, or contain errors that significantly affect understanding.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Tim After a Disaster: Not yet demonstrating clear communication.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>wr_01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>wr_02</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>disc_mod01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>
  </learningOutcomeGroup>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       NEW OUTCOME GROUP: TELEVISION HISTORY (TVST-101)
       Understanding 90s sitcom conventions and Home Improvement's place in TV history
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <learningOutcomeGroup identifier="og_television_history">
    <title>Television History: TVST-101 - The Golden Age of TGIF</title>
    <description>Comprehensive understanding of 1990s sitcom conventions, network television dynamics, and Home Improvement's significant place in American television history. Students explore how the series exemplifies and departed from genre conventions of the era.</description>

    <!-- TVST-101 Outcome: Network Television Landscape -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst101_network_landscape">
      <title>Analyze the 1990s Network Television Landscape</title>
      <description>Students will demonstrate comprehensive understanding of the network television ecosystem during Home Improvement's run (1991-1999), including ABC's programming strategy, the TGIF phenomenon, Must See TV competition, and how sitcoms functioned as cultural events before streaming fragmentation.</description>
      <calculation_method>decaying_average</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>75</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Demonstrates sophisticated understanding of 90s television industry dynamics. Articulates how network strategies, advertiser relationships, and family viewing habits shaped programming decisions. Connects Home Improvement's scheduling, ratings dominance, and cultural impact to broader industry trends. Compares ABC's approach to CBS and NBC strategies of the era.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Proficiently explains Home Improvement's position in 90s television. Identifies key competitors (Seinfeld, Friends, Frasier), understands TGIF's family audience strategy, and recognizes how the show's Detroit/blue-collar setting differentiated it from New York-centric sitcoms. Can explain syndication economics and rerun culture.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Developing awareness of television history context. Recognizes that Home Improvement was a major hit but may not fully articulate how network dynamics and cultural factors contributed to its success. Limited understanding of the pre-streaming television experience.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: Minimal engagement with television history. Views Home Improvement in isolation rather than as part of a broader media ecosystem. Cannot explain what made 90s network television distinct from contemporary streaming.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst101_week01</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst101_midterm</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- TVST-101 Outcome: Sitcom Genre Conventions -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst101_genre_conventions">
      <title>Identify and Analyze Sitcom Genre Conventions</title>
      <description>Students will identify defining conventions of the multi-camera sitcom format and explain how Home Improvement both adhered to and innovated within these conventions, including the three-act structure, A/B plot interweaving, cold opens, tag scenes, and the distinctive show-within-a-show format.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Expert command of sitcom conventions. Identifies how Home Improvement's Tool Time segments function as both cold opens and recurring structural element. Analyzes the fence scenes as a genre innovation combining exposition, philosophy, and emotional resolution. Explains how the studio audience affects timing and performance choices.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Solid understanding of sitcom structure. Identifies standard elements (teaser, act breaks, tag) and recognizes how Tool Time serves multiple narrative functions. Understands the "problem-complication-resolution" formula and how Home Improvement adapts it for domestic comedy.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Recognizes basic structural elements but may not articulate how Home Improvement innovates within conventions. Can identify when Tool Time segments occur but struggles to explain their narrative function.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: Limited awareness of genre conventions. Cannot distinguish structural elements or explain how sitcom formatting shapes viewer experience.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst101_week03</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst101_structure_analysis</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- TVST-101 Outcome: Television History Timeline -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst101_tv_history">
      <title>Place Home Improvement in Television History Timeline</title>
      <description>Students will situate Home Improvement within the broader arc of American television comedy, tracing influences from 1950s domestic sitcoms through Norman Lear's social comedy revolution, and explaining how the series connected past traditions while anticipating future developments.</description>
      <calculation_method>latest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Comprehensive historical perspective. Traces lineage from Father Knows Best and Leave It to Beaver through All in the Family and The Cosby Show to Home Improvement. Explains how Tim Allen's stand-up roots connect to the shift from writer-driven to performer-driven sitcoms. Identifies what Home Improvement predicted about future television comedy.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Strong historical awareness. Identifies Home Improvement's debts to earlier domestic comedies while recognizing its distinctive 90s sensibility. Can explain how the show balanced traditional family values with more progressive elements, positioning it within the "family values" debates of the era.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Basic historical awareness. Recognizes some precursors to Home Improvement but struggles to articulate specific influences or explain the show's place in television evolution.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: No demonstrated understanding of television history beyond Home Improvement itself. Cannot connect the series to predecessor or successor programs.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst101_final_paper</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst101_comparison_essay</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>
  </learningOutcomeGroup>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       NEW OUTCOME GROUP: CHARACTER ANALYSIS (TVST-102)
       Analyzing character development across 8 seasons
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <learningOutcomeGroup identifier="og_character_analysis">
    <title>Character Analysis: TVST-102 - Eight Seasons of Growth</title>
    <description>Advanced competencies in analyzing character development, relationship dynamics, and performance across Home Improvement's 204 episodes over 8 seasons. Students develop skills in tracking character arcs, analyzing ensemble dynamics, and understanding how sitcom characters balance consistency with growth.</description>

    <!-- TVST-102 Outcome: Character Arc Analysis -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst102_character_arcs">
      <title>Trace Long-Form Character Arcs Across Seasons</title>
      <description>Students will analyze how major characters evolved across 8 seasons while maintaining recognizable core traits, examining Tim's gradual maturation, Jill's career development, the boys' adolescent journeys, and Al's relationship evolution with demonstrations of deep textual knowledge.</description>
      <calculation_method>decaying_average</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>75</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Sophisticated arc analysis across full series. Tracks subtle character evolution with specific episode evidence. Identifies how Tim's relationship with his father's death shapes his parenting across seasons. Analyzes Jill's progression from homemaker to psychology student to professional. Explains how the boys' individual personalities emerged and developed. Recognizes character consistency even as growth occurred.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Solid understanding of character development. Identifies major arc milestones for main characters. Can explain how characters changed between early and late seasons. Understands the challenge of maintaining comedic character types while allowing realistic growth.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Recognizes that characters changed over time but provides limited specific evidence. May conflate actor aging with character development or miss subtler evolution in favor of obvious changes.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: Views characters as static types rather than evolving personalities. Cannot identify how characters in Season 8 differ from Season 1.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst102_arc_paper</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst102_season_comparison</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- TVST-102 Outcome: Ensemble Dynamics -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst102_ensemble">
      <title>Analyze Ensemble Cast Dynamics and Relationships</title>
      <description>Students will examine how the ensemble cast functioned as a comedic and dramatic unit, analyzing key relationships (Tim/Jill, Tim/Al, Tim/Wilson, brothers dynamic), understanding how characters serve as foils, and identifying how ensemble balance shifted across seasons.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Expert ensemble analysis. Explains how Al functions as Tim's professional foil while Wilson serves as his philosophical counterweight. Analyzes the Tim/Jill dynamic as genuine partnership that subverts sitcom stereotypes while sometimes reinforcing them. Tracks how the three boys differentiated as characters and how their relationships with parents evolved differently.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Strong understanding of character relationships. Identifies how pairings create comedy (Tim/Al banter) and emotional depth (Tim/Wilson conversations). Recognizes recurring patterns in how characters interact and support episode plots.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Basic awareness of character relationships but limited analysis of why certain pairings work. May focus on individual characters without examining ensemble dynamics.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: Cannot articulate how character relationships function comedically or dramatically. Sees characters in isolation rather than as part of an ensemble.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst102_relationship_analysis</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst102_foil_essay</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- TVST-102 Outcome: Performance Analysis -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst102_performance">
      <title>Evaluate Actor Performances and Character Creation</title>
      <description>Students will analyze how actors' performances shaped their characters, distinguishing between scripted characterization and performance choices, and evaluating how Tim Allen, Patricia Richardson, Richard Karn, and Jonathan Taylor Thomas contributed to character definition through physicality, timing, and interpretation.</description>
      <calculation_method>latest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Sophisticated performance analysis. Identifies how Tim Allen's physical comedy and signature grunt became character-defining elements beyond scripting. Analyzes Patricia Richardson's ability to ground absurd situations. Recognizes Earl Hindman's challenge of acting with obscured face. Distinguishes between what was written and what performers brought to roles.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Good awareness of performance contribution to character. Identifies signature performance elements (Tim's grunts, Al's "I don't think so, Tim"). Understands how multi-camera sitcom format shapes performance style differently from single-camera or film.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Some awareness of performance but limited ability to distinguish actor choices from character writing. May focus exclusively on dialogue without considering physical performance.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: No demonstrated ability to analyze performance separate from scripted character. Cannot identify what actors contribute beyond delivering lines.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst102_performance_analysis</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst102_final_project</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>
  </learningOutcomeGroup>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       NEW OUTCOME GROUP: CULTURAL STUDIES (TVST-103)
       Connecting themes to 90s American culture
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <learningOutcomeGroup identifier="og_cultural_studies">
    <title>Cultural Studies: TVST-103 - Home Improvement and the American 90s</title>
    <description>Critical analysis of how Home Improvement both reflected and shaped 1990s American culture, including examinations of masculinity, family values discourse, consumer culture, suburban identity, and the show's engagement with contemporary social issues.</description>

    <!-- TVST-103 Outcome: Masculinity and Gender -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst103_masculinity">
      <title>Analyze Representations of 1990s Masculinity</title>
      <description>Students will critically examine Home Improvement's complex portrayal of masculinity, analyzing how Tim Taylor simultaneously celebrates and critiques traditional masculine ideals, how the show engaged with the "crisis of masculinity" discourse of the 1990s, and how gender dynamics between Tim and Jill reflect and challenge period assumptions.</description>
      <calculation_method>decaying_average</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>75</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Nuanced masculinity analysis. Explains how Tim represents both aspirational and satirical masculinity simultaneously. Identifies how the show's comedy often critiques Tim's excesses while the narrative frequently validates his approaches. Analyzes how the three sons represent different masculine possibilities. Connects to broader 90s discourse around men's movements, Iron John, and changing gender expectations.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Strong gender analysis. Recognizes the show's ambivalent stance toward traditional masculinity. Identifies how Jill functions as both partner and corrective to Tim's excesses. Understands how Tool Time parodies hypermasculine DIY culture while celebrating competence.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Basic awareness of gender themes but analysis may be one-dimensional. May see the show as simply celebrating or simply mocking masculinity without recognizing complexity.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: No demonstrated ability to analyze gender representations. Takes character portrayals at face value without critical examination.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst103_masculinity_paper</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst103_gender_discussion</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- TVST-103 Outcome: Family Values Discourse -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst103_family_values">
      <title>Contextualize Within 1990s Family Values Discourse</title>
      <description>Students will analyze Home Improvement's engagement with the "family values" debates of the 1990s, understanding how the show positioned itself within cultural conversations about parenting, marriage, work-life balance, and the definition of the American family during the Clinton era.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Sophisticated cultural analysis. Contextualizes the Taylors within debates triggered by Dan Quayle's Murphy Brown speech and the broader culture wars. Analyzes how the show presents a "safe" two-parent household while occasionally acknowledging alternative family structures. Examines Jill's career trajectory as reflecting anxieties about women's workforce participation.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Good cultural context. Identifies how the Taylor family represents idealized middle-class suburban life. Recognizes episodes that directly address parenting challenges, marital conflict, and work-life balance. Understands the show's generally conservative family vision with progressive exceptions.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Some awareness of cultural context but limited ability to connect show content to specific 90s debates. May recognize family themes without placing them in historical context.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: No engagement with broader cultural context. Views family dynamics without connecting to period-specific cultural conversations.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst103_family_values_essay</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst103_cultural_context</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- TVST-103 Outcome: Consumer Culture and Class -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst103_consumer_culture">
      <title>Examine Class Identity and Consumer Culture</title>
      <description>Students will analyze how Home Improvement portrays middle-class suburban identity, consumerism, and the DIY movement of the 1990s, examining how Tool Time functions as both product placement vehicle and commentary on consumer culture, and how the Taylor household represents aspirational middle-class existence.</description>
      <calculation_method>latest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Sophisticated class and consumer analysis. Examines how Binford Tools sponsorship within the show mirrors actual product placement economics. Analyzes the Detroit setting's working-class associations against the Taylors' comfortable lifestyle. Connects Tim's obsession with "more power" to 90s consumer culture and technological enthusiasm. Identifies class markers in set design and character behavior.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Good awareness of economic themes. Recognizes how the show celebrates tool ownership and home improvement as masculine consumer activities. Identifies the aspirational elements of the Taylor household. Understands Tool Time as both workplace setting and consumer showcase.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Some awareness of consumer and class themes but analysis may be superficial. Recognizes product presence without deeper analysis of what it signifies.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: No demonstrated awareness of class or consumer themes. Does not recognize economic aspects of the show's worldview.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst103_consumer_analysis</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst103_final_exam</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>
  </learningOutcomeGroup>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       NEW OUTCOME GROUP: CREATIVE WRITING (TVST-104)
       Writing in the show's voice and format
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <learningOutcomeGroup identifier="og_creative_writing_advanced">
    <title>Creative Writing: TVST-104 - Writing for Tool Time</title>
    <description>Advanced creative writing competencies focused on television comedy writing, including mastery of sitcom format, character voice authenticity, comedic structure, and original content creation within established series parameters. Students develop professional-level television writing skills through Home Improvement-focused exercises.</description>

    <!-- TVST-104 Outcome: Sitcom Script Format -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst104_script_format">
      <title>Master Television Comedy Script Format</title>
      <description>Students will demonstrate professional mastery of multi-camera sitcom script format, including proper scene headings, action lines, dialogue formatting, act breaks, and timing conventions specific to the 22-minute broadcast format that Home Improvement utilized.</description>
      <calculation_method>decaying_average</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>75</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Professional-quality formatting. Scripts follow industry-standard multi-camera format precisely. Demonstrates understanding of how formatting conventions (CONTINUED, beat, V.O.) serve production needs. Properly structures cold open, two acts, and tag within appropriate page counts. Scene headings correctly indicate recurring Home Improvement locations (INT. TAYLOR KITCHEN, INT. TOOL TIME SET).</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Solid format competency. Scripts are properly formatted with correct dialogue spacing, parentheticals, and scene transitions. Demonstrates understanding of multi-camera vs. single-camera format differences. Appropriate length for television broadcast timing.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Basic format awareness with some errors. May mix multi-camera and film formatting conventions. Scripts may be significantly over or under appropriate length.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: Does not demonstrate awareness of professional script formatting. Presents content in prose or non-standard format.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst104_format_exercise</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst104_spec_script</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- TVST-104 Outcome: Character Voice Writing -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst104_character_voice">
      <title>Write Authentic Character Voices</title>
      <description>Students will create original dialogue that authentically captures established character voices, demonstrating ability to write for Tim, Jill, Al, Wilson, and the Taylor sons with appropriate vocabulary, speech patterns, humor styles, and character-specific verbal tics that feel consistent with the original series.</description>
      <calculation_method>highest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Exceptional voice authenticity. Original dialogue reads as indistinguishable from produced episodes. Tim's dialogue includes appropriate grunt sounds, tool puns, and masculine overreach. Al's responses include genuine "I don't think so, Tim" moments without over-reliance on catchphrases. Wilson's advice incorporates philosophical references with warmth. Jill's intelligence and exasperation balance appropriately.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Strong voice consistency. Characters are clearly distinguishable through dialogue alone. Captures key speech patterns without reducing characters to catchphrase machines. Original content feels like plausible extension of established characterization.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Recognizable but inconsistent voices. May rely too heavily on catchphrases or verbal tics. Some dialogue could be spoken by any character without clear distinction.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: Character voices not distinguishable. Dialogue is generic or inconsistent with established characterization.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst104_dialogue_workshop</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst104_scene_writing</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- TVST-104 Outcome: Comedy Writing -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst104_comedy_writing">
      <title>Construct Effective Sitcom Comedy</title>
      <description>Students will demonstrate understanding of comedic structure and timing in television writing, including setup-punchline construction, running gags, comic escalation, physical comedy description, and the balance between character-based humor and situation comedy that defined Home Improvement's comedic approach.</description>
      <calculation_method>decaying_average</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>75</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Sophisticated comedy construction. Demonstrates mastery of multiple joke types: verbal wit, physical comedy, callback humor, and character-based comedy. Comic escalation builds appropriately through scenes. Physical comedy is described with enough specificity for performance while leaving room for actor interpretation. Humor emerges naturally from character and situation rather than imposed jokes.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Effective comedy writing. Jokes land with appropriate setup and payoff. Understands the "rule of threes" and comic timing. Physical comedy moments (Tim's inevitable accidents) are plausible and funny. Balances laughs with story progression.</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Some effective comedy but inconsistent. May force jokes or miss timing opportunities. Physical comedy may be implausible or unclear in description.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: Comedy is absent, forced, or ineffective. Does not demonstrate understanding of sitcom comedic conventions.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst104_comedy_exercise</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst104_final_script</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>

    <!-- TVST-104 Outcome: Original Episode Creation -->
    <learningOutcome identifier="lo_tvst104_episode_creation">
      <title>Create Original Episode Concepts and Stories</title>
      <description>Students will develop original, producible episode concepts that fit within Home Improvement's established parameters, including A/B story construction, thematic coherence, appropriate scope for television production, and stories that serve character development while delivering entertainment value.</description>
      <calculation_method>latest</calculation_method>
      <calculation_int>65</calculation_int>
      <mastery_points>3</mastery_points>
      <points_possible>3</points_possible>

      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Exceeds Mastery: Exceptional episode conception. Original story feels like undiscovered episode from the series. A-plot and B-plot connect thematically while allowing different cast members to shine. Story is producible within standard sitcom budget and location constraints. Episode advances ongoing character relationships while telling complete standalone story. Wilson's fence scene advice connects organically to episode theme.</description>
          <points>3</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Mastery: Strong episode development. Story concept is original and appropriate for the series. A/B structure is present and functional. Story serves characters and provides entertainment. Production constraints are considered (limited locations, appropriate cast usage).</description>
          <points>2</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Near Mastery: Workable concept with execution issues. May have single-plot structure or imbalanced A/B stories. Story may not feel distinctively like Home Improvement or may ignore production realities.</description>
          <points>1</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Below Mastery: Episode concept is unoriginal, unproducible, or fundamentally inconsistent with the series. Does not demonstrate understanding of television storytelling requirements.</description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>

      <alignments>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst104_story_pitch</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst104_final_script</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
        <alignment>
          <content_type>Assignment</content_type>
          <content_id>tvst104_portfolio</content_id>
          <mastery_type>criteria</mastery_type>
        </alignment>
      </alignments>
    </learningOutcome>
  </learningOutcomeGroup>

</learningOutcomes>
