<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rubrics xmlns="http://canvas.instructure.com/xsd/cccv1p0"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://canvas.instructure.com/xsd/cccv1p0 http://canvas.instructure.com/xsd/cccv1p0.xsd">

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       TOOL TIME UNIVERSITY - COMPREHENSIVE GRADING RUBRICS

       Rating Scale:
       - Excellent (4): 90-100% - Master Craftsman level
       - Good (3): 80-89% - Journeyman Builder level
       - Satisfactory (2): 70-79% - Apprentice level
       - Needs Work (1): 60-69% - Weekend Warrior level
       - Not Demonstrated (0): Below 60% - Tim After a Disaster

       Home Equity Points System - Where knowledge builds value!
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       1. TOOL TIME CHALLENGE RUBRIC
       For creative projects and major analytical assignments ($2,500 each)

       Criteria Distribution:
       - Fan Authenticity (25%) - $625
       - Analysis Depth (25%) - $625
       - Creativity (25%) - $625
       - Presentation (25%) - $625
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <rubric identifier="rubric_tool_time_challenge">
    <title>Tool Time Challenge Rubric</title>
    <description>Assessment rubric for Tool Time Challenge creative projects ($2,500 Home Equity). Evaluates fan authenticity, analytical depth, creative expression, and professional presentation.</description>
    <points_possible>2500</points_possible>
    <free_form_criterion_comments>true</free_form_criterion_comments>
    <hide_score_total>false</hide_score_total>

    <!-- Fan Authenticity (25%) -->
    <criterion identifier="ttc_crit_authenticity">
      <description>Fan Authenticity</description>
      <long_description>Demonstrates genuine knowledge and appreciation of Home Improvement. Uses accurate episode details, character knowledge, and show-specific references that reveal deep familiarity with the series.</long_description>
      <points>625</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Exceptional fan knowledge on display. References obscure episodes, understands character arcs across seasons, correctly identifies guest stars, running jokes, and production details. Could host a Tool Time trivia night.</long_description>
          <points>625</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong fan knowledge evident. Accurately references multiple episodes and characters. Understands show dynamics and history. Knows the difference between seasons 1 and 8 Tim.</long_description>
          <points>500</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate fan knowledge. Gets major characters and famous episodes right but may confuse details or rely on common knowledge. Could name the Taylor boys but might mix up their plotlines.</long_description>
          <points>375</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Limited fan knowledge. May contain factual errors about characters or episodes. Relies heavily on Wikipedia-level information. Confuses Al's beard phase with his pre-beard era.</long_description>
          <points>250</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No authentic fan knowledge. Significant errors or clearly hasn't watched the show. Thinks Wilson's first name is revealed in the pilot.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Analysis Depth (25%) -->
    <criterion identifier="ttc_crit_analysis">
      <description>Analysis Depth</description>
      <long_description>Goes beyond surface observations to reveal meaningful patterns, themes, and insights. Demonstrates critical thinking about the show's construction, social commentary, and cultural significance.</long_description>
      <points>625</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Exceptional analytical depth. Reveals sophisticated patterns others miss. Connects show elements to broader cultural, social, or comedic contexts. Analysis illuminates why the show resonated with audiences for 8 seasons.</long_description>
          <points>625</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong analysis with clear insights. Identifies meaningful patterns and makes thoughtful connections. Goes beyond "Tim is funny" to explore why specific comedic choices work.</long_description>
          <points>500</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate analysis that makes some good points but stays relatively surface-level. Observations are accurate but don't reveal new understanding.</long_description>
          <points>375</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Shallow analysis that primarily summarizes rather than analyzes. States the obvious without exploring significance. "Tim causes problems" without examining why or what it means.</long_description>
          <points>250</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No meaningful analysis. Pure summary or observations unrelated to analytical framework.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Creativity (25%) -->
    <criterion identifier="ttc_crit_creativity">
      <description>Creativity</description>
      <long_description>Demonstrates original thinking and creative approach to the assignment. Takes risks, offers unique perspectives, and approaches the material in fresh ways while honoring the source.</long_description>
      <points>625</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Highly creative and original. Approaches the assignment in unexpected ways that delight and surprise. Takes creative risks that pay off. The kind of work that makes graders say "Why didn't I think of that?"</long_description>
          <points>625</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Creative approach with several original elements. Shows independent thinking and personal voice. Goes beyond obvious choices to find interesting angles.</long_description>
          <points>500</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Some creative elements but largely follows expected approaches. Safe choices that work but don't stand out. Like Tim using a power tool without modifying it.</long_description>
          <points>375</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Limited creativity. Follows the most obvious path without personal interpretation. Generic approach that could apply to any show.</long_description>
          <points>250</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No creative effort evident. Bare minimum completion or copied approach.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Presentation (25%) -->
    <criterion identifier="ttc_crit_presentation">
      <description>Presentation</description>
      <long_description>Professional presentation with clear organization, appropriate formatting, and polished delivery. Visual elements (if applicable) enhance rather than distract from content.</long_description>
      <points>625</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Exceptional presentation quality. Polished, professional, and visually appealing. Organization enhances understanding. Could be featured in Binford's employee newsletter.</long_description>
          <points>625</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong presentation with good organization and few errors. Formatting is consistent and professional. Easy to follow and navigate.</long_description>
          <points>500</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate presentation with some organizational or formatting issues. Content is accessible but presentation doesn't enhance it.</long_description>
          <points>375</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Poor presentation that detracts from content. Disorganized, hard to follow, or contains many formatting errors.</long_description>
          <points>250</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>Unprofessional presentation. No apparent organization or formatting. Like Tim's garage after a project gone wrong.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>
  </rubric>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       2. BINFORD PROJECT CARD RUBRIC
       For hands-on assignments and practical analysis projects ($1,500 each)

       Criteria Distribution:
       - Technical Accuracy (30%) - $450
       - Show Knowledge (30%) - $450
       - Completeness (20%) - $300
       - Organization (20%) - $300
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <rubric identifier="rubric_binford_project_card">
    <title>Binford Project Card Rubric</title>
    <description>Assessment rubric for Binford Project Card hands-on assignments ($1,500 Home Equity). Evaluates technical accuracy, show knowledge, completeness, and organization.</description>
    <points_possible>1500</points_possible>
    <free_form_criterion_comments>true</free_form_criterion_comments>
    <hide_score_total>false</hide_score_total>

    <!-- Technical Accuracy (30%) -->
    <criterion identifier="bpc_crit_technical">
      <description>Technical Accuracy</description>
      <long_description>Demonstrates accurate understanding of tools, techniques, or technical concepts referenced in the show. Information about actual tools, construction methods, or DIY principles is correct and well-researched.</long_description>
      <points>450</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Impeccable technical accuracy. All tool references, construction terminology, and DIY concepts are correct. Shows real understanding of whether Tim's modifications would actually work (spoiler: they wouldn't). Al Borland-approved.</long_description>
          <points>450</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong technical accuracy with minor exceptions. Understands the difference between Tim's fantasy physics and actual tool operation. Gets the important details right.</long_description>
          <points>360</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Generally accurate but contains some technical errors or oversimplifications. Knows power tools exist but might confuse a jigsaw with a circular saw.</long_description>
          <points>270</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Multiple technical inaccuracies. Shows limited understanding of actual tool operation or construction principles referenced in assignments.</long_description>
          <points>180</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>Significant technical errors throughout. Demonstrates Tim-level understanding of tool safety (which is not a compliment).</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Show Knowledge (30%) -->
    <criterion identifier="bpc_crit_show_knowledge">
      <description>Show Knowledge</description>
      <long_description>Demonstrates comprehensive knowledge of Home Improvement episodes, characters, running gags, and production history. Uses this knowledge accurately and appropriately.</long_description>
      <points>450</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Expert-level show knowledge. Correctly references specific episodes, knows character histories, understands show evolution across seasons. Can distinguish between early-season and late-season dynamics.</long_description>
          <points>450</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong show knowledge. Accurately discusses characters, remembers key episodes, and understands show's structure. Knows why "I don't think so, Tim" became iconic.</long_description>
          <points>360</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate show knowledge focused on major elements. May miss nuances or confuse some details. Knows the main characters but might forget Heidi replaced Lisa.</long_description>
          <points>270</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Limited show knowledge with noticeable gaps. May rely on general sitcom knowledge rather than Home Improvement specifics.</long_description>
          <points>180</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>Insufficient show knowledge. Major errors or clearly unfamiliar with the series.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Completeness (20%) -->
    <criterion identifier="bpc_crit_completeness">
      <description>Completeness</description>
      <long_description>Addresses all required elements of the assignment with appropriate depth. No major components missing or underdeveloped.</long_description>
      <points>300</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>All requirements addressed thoroughly and then some. Goes beyond minimum expectations to provide comprehensive coverage. Every section fully developed with appropriate detail.</long_description>
          <points>300</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>All requirements addressed with good detail. Complete submission that meets expectations. Nothing missing or significantly underdeveloped.</long_description>
          <points>240</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Most requirements addressed but some sections may lack depth. Generally complete but uneven development across components.</long_description>
          <points>180</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Several requirements missing or insufficiently developed. Incomplete submission that needs significant additions.</long_description>
          <points>120</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>Major requirements missing. Submission is substantially incomplete.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Organization (20%) -->
    <criterion identifier="bpc_crit_organization">
      <description>Organization</description>
      <long_description>Clear, logical structure that guides the reader through the content. Appropriate headings, transitions, and formatting that enhance comprehension.</long_description>
      <points>300</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Impeccably organized. Logical flow that enhances understanding. Professional formatting with clear sections and smooth transitions. Like Al's perfectly organized tool wall.</long_description>
          <points>300</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Well organized with clear structure. Easy to navigate and follow. Good use of headings and logical progression of ideas.</long_description>
          <points>240</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequately organized but could be clearer. Some sections may feel out of place or transitions may be abrupt.</long_description>
          <points>180</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Poorly organized. Difficult to follow or find information. Lacks clear structure or logical progression.</long_description>
          <points>120</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No discernible organization. Stream of consciousness or random arrangement. Like Tim's garage mid-project.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>
  </rubric>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       3. WILSON'S REFLECTION RUBRIC
       For philosophical essays and reflective writing ($2,000 each)

       Criteria Distribution:
       - Cultural Reference Quality (25%) - $500
       - Philosophical Depth (25%) - $500
       - Connection to Show (25%) - $500
       - Writing Quality (25%) - $500
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <rubric identifier="rubric_wilsons_reflection">
    <title>Wilson's Reflection Rubric</title>
    <description>Assessment rubric for Wilson's Reflection philosophical essays ($2,000 Home Equity). Evaluates cultural reference quality, philosophical depth, connection to the show, and writing quality.</description>
    <points_possible>2000</points_possible>
    <free_form_criterion_comments>true</free_form_criterion_comments>
    <hide_score_total>false</hide_score_total>

    <!-- Cultural Reference Quality (25%) -->
    <criterion identifier="wr_crit_cultural">
      <description>Cultural Reference Quality</description>
      <long_description>Incorporates relevant cultural, literary, or historical references in the style of Wilson. References are accurate, appropriately sourced, and enhance the reflection rather than just decorating it.</long_description>
      <points>500</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Exceptional use of cultural references. Quotes are accurate, sources are legitimate, and references illuminate the topic in unexpected ways. Wilson would lean over the fence nodding approvingly.</long_description>
          <points>500</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong cultural references that enhance the essay. Sources are credible and quotes are accurate. References connect meaningfully to the topic.</long_description>
          <points>400</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate cultural references but may be surface-level, slightly inaccurate, or not fully integrated into the argument.</long_description>
          <points>300</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Limited or poor cultural references. May use made-up quotes, misattribute sources, or include references that don't connect to the topic.</long_description>
          <points>200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No cultural references or references are fabricated/grossly inaccurate.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Philosophical Depth (25%) -->
    <criterion identifier="wr_crit_philosophical">
      <description>Philosophical Depth</description>
      <long_description>Engages meaningfully with philosophical concepts, ethical questions, or deeper meanings. Goes beyond surface observations to explore why things matter and what they reveal about human experience.</long_description>
      <points>500</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Profound philosophical engagement. Wrestles with complex ideas, considers multiple perspectives, and arrives at thoughtful insights. Demonstrates genuine intellectual growth through the reflection process.</long_description>
          <points>500</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong philosophical thinking. Moves beyond obvious observations to explore deeper meaning. Shows evidence of genuine reflection and consideration of implications.</long_description>
          <points>400</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate philosophical engagement but may stay relatively safe or surface-level. Some deeper thinking present but not fully developed.</long_description>
          <points>300</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Shallow philosophical engagement. Presents observations without exploring their meaning or significance. Describes what happened rather than what it means.</long_description>
          <points>200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No philosophical depth. Pure summary or observations without reflection.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Connection to Show (25%) -->
    <criterion identifier="wr_crit_connection">
      <description>Connection to Show</description>
      <long_description>Effectively bridges philosophical ideas with specific elements from Home Improvement. Uses episodes, characters, or themes as launching points for deeper exploration rather than just examples.</long_description>
      <points>500</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Seamless integration of show and philosophy. Uses Home Improvement elements not just as illustrations but as genuine sources of insight. The show becomes a lens for understanding bigger ideas.</long_description>
          <points>500</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong connection between show and philosophical content. Examples from the show meaningfully support and illuminate the reflection.</long_description>
          <points>400</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate connection but may feel forced or superficial. Show references present but not deeply integrated with philosophical content.</long_description>
          <points>300</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Weak connection between show and reflection. Show elements feel tacked on or the essay could work equally well about any sitcom.</long_description>
          <points>200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No meaningful connection to Home Improvement. Essay doesn't engage with show content.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Writing Quality (25%) -->
    <criterion identifier="wr_crit_writing">
      <description>Writing Quality</description>
      <long_description>Clear, engaging prose appropriate for reflective philosophical writing. Voice is authentic, language is precise, and the writing itself becomes a vehicle for meaning rather than an obstacle to it.</long_description>
      <points>500</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Exceptional writing that elevates the content. Prose is clear yet nuanced, voice is authentic, and language choices enhance meaning. Wilson would appreciate the eloquence.</long_description>
          <points>500</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong writing with clear expression and few errors. Voice is consistent and appropriate for reflective essay. Engaging to read.</long_description>
          <points>400</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate writing that communicates ideas but may lack polish or distinctiveness. Some errors or awkward expressions but nothing that impedes understanding.</long_description>
          <points>300</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Writing detracts from content. Frequent errors, unclear expressions, or inappropriate tone for reflective essay.</long_description>
          <points>200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>Writing fails to communicate ideas effectively. Too many errors or unclear prose to evaluate content.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>
  </rubric>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       4. FINAL PROJECT RUBRIC
       For Master Craftsman Episode Script ($10,000)

       Criteria Distribution:
       - Character Voice Authenticity (20%) - $2,000
       - Plot Structure (20%) - $2,000
       - Humor/Tone (20%) - $2,000
       - Tool Time Segment (20%) - $2,000
       - Wilson Wisdom Integration (20%) - $2,000
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <rubric identifier="rubric_final_project">
    <title>Master Craftsman Final Project Rubric</title>
    <description>Assessment rubric for the final episode script writing project ($10,000 Home Equity). Evaluates character voice authenticity, plot structure, humor/tone, Tool Time segment, and Wilson wisdom integration.</description>
    <points_possible>10000</points_possible>
    <free_form_criterion_comments>true</free_form_criterion_comments>
    <hide_score_total>false</hide_score_total>

    <!-- Character Voice Authenticity (20%) -->
    <criterion identifier="final_crit_voice">
      <description>Character Voice Authenticity</description>
      <long_description>Captures authentic character voices in dialogue and action. Tim's macho posturing and vulnerability, Al's long-suffering patience, Jill's intelligence and exasperation, Wilson's gentle wisdom, and the boys' distinct personalities all ring true to the show.</long_description>
      <points>2000</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Exceptional voice capture across all characters. Every line of dialogue sounds exactly like the character would say it. Captures not just catchphrases but the rhythm, vocabulary, and emotional patterns unique to each character. Could air on ABC tomorrow.</long_description>
          <points>2000</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong voice work with characters clearly recognizable. Dialogue feels natural for most characters. May occasionally rely too heavily on catchphrases but demonstrates real understanding of character voices.</long_description>
          <points>1600</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate voice capture with some inconsistencies. Main characters recognizable but may feel generic at times. Secondary characters may blend together.</long_description>
          <points>1200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Weak character voices. Characters say things they wouldn't say or in ways they wouldn't say them. May capture the general idea but misses the specifics that make each character unique.</long_description>
          <points>800</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No authentic character voices. Characters are interchangeable or completely out of character. Generic sitcom dialogue rather than Home Improvement-specific voices.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Plot Structure (20%) -->
    <criterion identifier="final_crit_structure">
      <description>Plot Structure</description>
      <long_description>Follows proper sitcom episode structure with A-plot (usually Tim's main conflict), B-plot (supporting family story), and appropriate act breaks. Story arc fits the 22-minute format with setup, complication, and resolution.</long_description>
      <points>2000</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Perfect episode structure. A and B plots interweave organically, each with clear setup, escalation, and resolution. Act breaks hit at natural dramatic moments. Pacing feels exactly like an actual Home Improvement episode.</long_description>
          <points>2000</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong structure with clear A and B plots that resolve appropriately. Minor pacing issues but overall feels like a complete episode. All structural elements present and functional.</long_description>
          <points>1600</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate structure but may feel rushed or unbalanced. A-plot clear but B-plot may be underdeveloped. Some structural elements present but not fully realized.</long_description>
          <points>1200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Weak structure. Missing subplot, unclear resolution, or pacing significantly off. Feels more like a sketch than an episode.</long_description>
          <points>800</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No recognizable episode structure. No clear plot arc or resolution. Collection of scenes without cohesive story.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Humor/Tone (20%) -->
    <criterion identifier="final_crit_humor">
      <description>Humor/Tone</description>
      <long_description>Captures the show's specific brand of humor: physical comedy, Tim's ego deflations, Al's dry comebacks, family warmth underneath the jokes. Balances comedy with heart in the Home Improvement tradition.</long_description>
      <points>2000</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Hilarious and heartfelt in equal measure. Original jokes that feel like they belong in the show. Physical comedy opportunities, callback humor, and emotional beats all land perfectly. Would generate genuine laughs and awws from the studio audience.</long_description>
          <points>2000</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong humor that fits the show's style. Good balance of comedy and heart. Most jokes work and tone remains consistent. A few standout moments.</long_description>
          <points>1600</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate humor but may not quite capture the show's specific style. Some jokes land, others fall flat. Tone may be inconsistent or lean too heavily in one direction.</long_description>
          <points>1200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Humor doesn't feel like Home Improvement. Jokes may be too crude, too sophisticated, or just not funny. Tone is off - either too dark or too saccharine.</long_description>
          <points>800</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No effective humor or completely wrong tone for the show. Neither funny nor heartfelt.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Tool Time Segment (20%) -->
    <criterion identifier="final_crit_tooltime">
      <description>Tool Time Segment</description>
      <long_description>Includes an authentic Tool Time segment that connects thematically to the episode's main story. Features appropriate Tim/Al dynamic, plausible project, and inevitable Tim disaster or close call.</long_description>
      <points>2000</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Perfect Tool Time segment. Project is plausible and interesting. Tim/Al banter is pitch-perfect. The segment connects meaningfully to the episode's theme. Tim's inevitable overreach feels natural and funny. Heidi's introductions feel authentic.</long_description>
          <points>2000</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong Tool Time segment with good Tim/Al interaction. Project makes sense and disaster/near-disaster is appropriately timed. Clear thematic connection to main story.</long_description>
          <points>1600</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate Tool Time segment but may feel underdeveloped or disconnected from main plot. Tim/Al dynamic present but not fully utilized.</long_description>
          <points>1200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Weak Tool Time segment. Project is unrealistic or boring. Tim/Al dynamic is off. No meaningful connection to episode theme.</long_description>
          <points>800</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No Tool Time segment or segment is so off-base it doesn't function as Tool Time.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <!-- Wilson Wisdom Integration (20%) -->
    <criterion identifier="final_crit_wilson">
      <description>Wilson Wisdom Integration</description>
      <long_description>Features an authentic Wilson fence scene with real philosophical or cultural reference. Wilson's advice illuminates the episode's theme and helps Tim (or another character) reach understanding without being preachy.</long_description>
      <points>2000</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Perfect Wilson scene. Uses real, accurately sourced philosophical/cultural reference. Advice connects organically to the episode's theme. Wilson's personality shines - wise but never condescending, obscure but accessible. The misunderstanding/clarification pattern is natural.</long_description>
          <points>2000</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong Wilson scene with appropriate philosophical reference. Advice connects to theme and helps move the story forward. Wilson's voice is recognizable and the fence dynamic works.</long_description>
          <points>1600</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate Wilson scene but philosophy may feel forced, misapplied, or only loosely connected to the story. Wilson is present but his unique voice may be muted.</long_description>
          <points>1200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Weak Wilson scene. Philosophy is generic, made up, or misquoted. Advice doesn't connect to story or Wilson sounds like a generic wise neighbor rather than Wilson specifically.</long_description>
          <points>800</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No Wilson scene or Wilson scene doesn't function as wisdom delivery. Missing the philosophical element entirely or completely misunderstands Wilson's role.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>
  </rubric>

  <!-- ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════
       DISCUSSION RUBRIC
       For discussion forum participation ($500 each)
       (Retained from original for discussion assignments)
       ═══════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════ -->
  <rubric identifier="rubric_discussion">
    <title>Discussion Rubric</title>
    <description>Assessment rubric for discussion forum participation ($500 Home Equity)</description>
    <points_possible>500</points_possible>
    <free_form_criterion_comments>true</free_form_criterion_comments>
    <hide_score_total>false</hide_score_total>

    <criterion identifier="disc_crit_initial">
      <description>Initial Post Quality</description>
      <long_description>Addresses prompt thoughtfully with specific examples and analysis. Meets word count (200-300 words).</long_description>
      <points>250</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Exceptional initial post that advances the discussion. Offers original insight with strong examples from the show.</long_description>
          <points>250</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Strong post addressing prompt with good analysis and examples.</long_description>
          <points>200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Adequate post but may lack depth or specific examples.</long_description>
          <points>150</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Basic post that minimally addresses prompt. Under word count or lacking analysis.</long_description>
          <points>100</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>Post does not address prompt or is too brief to evaluate.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>

    <criterion identifier="disc_crit_replies">
      <description>Peer Responses</description>
      <long_description>Two substantive replies (75+ words each) that engage meaningfully with classmates' ideas.</long_description>
      <points>250</points>
      <criterion_use_range>true</criterion_use_range>
      <ratings>
        <rating>
          <description>Excellent (4)</description>
          <long_description>Two excellent replies that extend the conversation. Asks questions, offers new perspectives, builds on classmates' ideas.</long_description>
          <points>250</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Good (3)</description>
          <long_description>Two good replies that engage substantively with classmates' posts.</long_description>
          <points>200</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Satisfactory (2)</description>
          <long_description>Two replies but one or both may be superficial or under word count.</long_description>
          <points>150</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Needs Work (1)</description>
          <long_description>Only one reply, or replies are "Great post!" style without substance.</long_description>
          <points>100</points>
        </rating>
        <rating>
          <description>Not Demonstrated (0)</description>
          <long_description>No peer replies or replies don't engage with classmates' ideas.</long_description>
          <points>0</points>
        </rating>
      </ratings>
    </criterion>
  </rubric>

</rubrics>
